Loyalty has a scent. And it smells like rebellion.
Isle of Dogs is a adventure, comedy, animation film directed by Wes Anderson.
In the future, an outbreak of canine flu leads the mayor of a Japanese
city to banish all dogs to an island used as a garbage dump.
The outcasts must soon embark on an epic journey when a 12-year-old
boy arrives on the island to find his beloved pet.
Chief (voice), played by Bryan Cranston.
Atari Kobayashi (voice), played by Koyu Rankin.
King (voice), played by Bob Balaban.
Rex (voice), played by Edward Norton.
Boss (voice), played by Bill Murray.
Duke (voice), played by Jeff Goldblum.
Isle of Dogs (Japanese: 犬ヶ島, Hepburn: Inu ga Shima) is a 2018 adult stop-motion animated science fiction
comedy-drama film written, produced, and directed by Wes Anderson, narrated by Courtney B.
Vance and starring an ensemble cast consisting of Bryan Cranston, Koyu Rankin, Edward Norton, Liev Schreiber, Bill Murray, Bob Balaban, Jeff
Goldblum, Scarlett Johansson, Kunichi Nomura, Tilda Swinton, Ken Watanabe, Akira Ito, Greta Gerwig, Akira Takayama, Frances McDormand, F.
Murray Abraham, Yojiro Noda, Fisher Stevens, Mari Natsuki, Nijiro
Murakami, Yoko Ono, Harvey Keitel and Frank Wood.
An American-German-British co-production, Isle of Dogs was produced by Studio Babelsberg and Indian
Paintbrush in association with Anderson's own company American Empirical Pictures.
This was Anderson's second stop-motion film, following Fantastic Mr.
The film is set in the fictional Japanese city of Megasaki where Mayor Kenji Kobayashi
has banished all dogs to Trash Island due to a canine influenza pandemic.
Kobayashi's nephew Atari sets out to find his missing dog Spots with
the help of a group of dogs led by stray dog Chief.
Anderson started developing the film in October 2015 using stop-motion
animation, with a voice cast of Norton, Cranston and Balaban.
It draws inspiration from films by Akira Kurosawa and Hayao Miyazaki, as well as the stop-motion animated holiday
specials made by Rankin/Bass Productions, the 1982 animated film The Plague Dogs, and Disney's 101 Dalmatians.
Production began in October 2016 at the 3 Mills Studios in East London.
By December 2016, Fox Searchlight Pictures acquired worldwide
distribution rights to the film, scheduling it for a 2018 release.
It is the second animated film to be released by Fox
Searchlight, seventeen years after Waking Life in 2001.
It is the only  20th Century Fox Animation film to
be released by Fox Searchlight.
Isle of Dogs opened the 68th Berlin International Film Festival, where
Anderson was awarded the Silver Bear for Best Director.
It was given a limited release in the United States on March
23, 2018, and went on wide release on April 13.
It grossed over $64 million worldwide, and received critical acclaim for its animation, story, musical
score, and deadpan humor, along with criticism for its portrayal of Japanese people and culture.
The film received two nominations at the 91st Academy
Awards, for Best Animated Feature and Best Score.
The film explores themes of island, japan, stop motion, dog, garbage dump.
The tone is lighthearted.